<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>radu&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://radu-matei.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on radu&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/matei_radu&#34; rel=&#34;noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Radu M&lt;/a&gt; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://radu-matei.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Best of Both worlds: Azure App Service and Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/k8s-appsvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/k8s-appsvc/</guid>
      <description>In this article we will explore how to integrate Azure App Service and Kubernetes within the same Azure Virtual Network and consume Kubernetes services from an Azure App Service app without exposing them on the public Internet. There will be lots of situations when we want to use both the simplicity and features of a PaaS service (such as autoscaling, easy SSL, or any other cool feature) for a component and the flexibility of Kubernetes for others - in this article we will see how to achieve this without exposing services on the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins pipelines with Kubernetes </title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/kubernetes-jenkins-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/kubernetes-jenkins-azure/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this article is to show you how to deploy Jenkins to your Kuberentes cluster using Helm and write Jenkins pipelines that execute builds within pods in your cluster - all of this while replicating your Jenkins configuration and persisting everything with Kubernetes persistent storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started with Helm and Draft for Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/k8s-helm-draft-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/k8s-helm-draft-azure/</guid>
      <description>This post shows you how to automatize and simplify working with multiple Kubernetes clusters and multiple tools such as kubectl, helm or draft - creating a container image with your desired version of the tools and mounting the config files to the container</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes 1.8 on Azure</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/k8s18-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/k8s18-azure/</guid>
      <description>In this post you&amp;rsquo;ll see how to deploy Kubernetes 1.8 and later on Azure using ACS Engine, an open-source tool that creates the entire configuration for your orchestration cluster and deploys it on Azure Container Service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hybrid Cluster: A CI/CD Story [Part 1] - Configuring a hybrid swarm mode cluster in Azure with acs-engine</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/hybrid-swarmmode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/hybrid-swarmmode/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to create a hybrid Docker Swarm Mode cluster with Linux and Windows agents, deploy it on Azure Container Service using ACS Engine, see how to connect to the cluster and manage it and finally how to deploy hybrid services with both Linux and Windows Server containers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
