<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>radu&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://radu-matei.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on radu&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/matei_radu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Radu M&lt;/a&gt; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://radu-matei.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a WebSockets middleware for ASP .NET Core 3</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-websockets-middleware/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-websockets-middleware/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll explore the low-level websockets API in .NET Core, understand the Middleware concept and finally write a websocket manager middleware that handles communication between various clients and your ASP.NET Core application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dockerizing an ASP.NET Core application with GitHub, Docker Cloud and Azure</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-docker-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-docker-azure/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will take the simplest ASP.NET Core application, run it with Docker locally, then create Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment flows using a GitHub repository, Docker Cloud and an Azure virtual machine that will act as a node for Docker Cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started with Raspberry Pi3, Sense HAT and Azure IoT Suite</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/rpi-sensehat-telemetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/rpi-sensehat-telemetry/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, we will get started with the Raspberry Pi3, the Sense HAT and Azure IoT Suite. More specifically, from the IoT Suite we will use IoT Hub, and Stream Analytics, and the end goal of this little project is to acquire data from the sensors, upload the data to IoT Hub, which feeds it into Stream Analytics, with outputs to an Azure SQL database (for storage) and to Service Bus (for consuming the data in real-time from various applications).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core MVC and SignalR Core</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-mvc-signalr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-mvc-signalr/</guid>
      <description>In this article we will explore how to get started with the Alpha 2 version of SignalR for ASP.NET Core 2.0 and understand streaming, sending binary data, using the Redis scaleout and, of course, chat!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inject ASP.NET Core Dependencies from JSON files</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-json-dependency-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-json-dependency-injection/</guid>
      <description>Back in the days of ASP.NET 4.x, each of the framework components - MVC, WebAPI, OWIN, SignalR - had its own dependency resolver and its own way of integrating with the framework. ASP.NET Core brings a consistent dependency injection mechanism with a unified meaning for lifetime or service registration,that is designed to server the needs of the framework and most consumer applications built on it. In this article, we will see a way of defining the service types and the implementation types we want to use based on a JSON file and switch between implementations without changing the code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
