<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vscode on radu&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://radu-matei.com/tags/vscode/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vscode on radu&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/matei_radu&#34; rel=&#34;noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Radu M&lt;/a&gt; 2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://radu-matei.com/tags/vscode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug Helm and Tiller using VS Code and Draft</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/debug-helm-tiller/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/debug-helm-tiller/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s article we will explore how to take a real-world application and start developing, debugging and deploying it to a Kubernetes cluster and how to use a couple of open-source tools to make our lives easier in the process. Specifically, we will use Helm, the package manager for Kubernetes , the newly released Kubernetes extension for VS Code and Draft to develop, debug and deploy is Helm itself.
 Helm helps you manage Kubernetes applications — Helm Charts help you define, install, and upgrade even the most complex Kubernetes application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Draft to develop front-end &#43; back-end applications. Experimenting with Draft, VS Code and remote debugging.</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/real-world-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/real-world-draft/</guid>
      <description>Application containers have skyrocketed in popularity over the last few years. In recent months, Kubernetes has emerged as a popular solution for orchestrating these containers. While many turn to Kubernetes for its extensible architecture and vibrant open-source community, some still view Kubernetes as too difficult to use. Learn how to use Draft to simplify your cloud-native application development!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>