<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vscode on Radu Matei&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://radu-matei.com/categories/vscode/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vscode on Radu Matei&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://radu-matei.com/categories/vscode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug Helm and Tiller using VS Code and Draft</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/debgg-helm-tiller/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/debgg-helm-tiller/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Debugging the Helm CLI Debugging Tiller  Building the Tiller binary for debugging Creating the Docker image, pushing it to a registry The Helm template for our deployment Putting it all together. Start debugging with VS Code  Conclusion  Introduction In today&amp;rsquo;s article we will explore how to take a real-world application and start developing, debugging and deploying it to a Kubernetes cluster and how to use a couple of open-source tools to make our lives easier in the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Draft to develop front-end &#43; back-end applications. Experimenting with Draft, VS Code and remote debugging.</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/real-world-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/real-world-draft/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Prerequisites Develop, deploy and debug front-end + back-end apps on Kubernetes  Deploy the Node back-end Exploring the Angular front-end Updating the back-end Experimenting with VS Code and remote debugging  Conclusion  Introduction  Application containers have skyrocketed in popularity over the last few years. In recent months, Kubernetes has emerged as a popular solution for orchestrating these containers. While many turn to Kubernetes for its extensible architecture and vibrant open-source community, some still view Kubernetes as too difficult to use.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>