<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>radu&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://radu-matei.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on radu&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/matei_radu&#34; rel=&#34;noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Radu M&lt;/a&gt; 2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://radu-matei.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to ASP .NET Core MVC API</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-api/</guid>
      <description>In this article we will be looking at ASP .NET Core MVC, more specifically at how to build an API that can be consumed from any type of application, be it web, mobile or desktop. We will build a very simple application that will enable the creation of posts (much like messages) and that will take us through adding the MVC services, creating models, controllers and consuming some data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP .NET Core JSON Configuration and Dependency Injection</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-configuration-greeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-configuration-greeting/</guid>
      <description>The new configuration system provides support for JSON, XML, INI and for in-memory configuration, while also allowing you to create your custom configuration provider. Let&amp;rsquo;s assume that in our application we want the response messages not to be hard-coded in Startup anymore, but stored in a configuration file so we don&amp;rsquo;t have to stop, modify or recompile our application every time the messages or the routes change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP .NET Core Routing</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-routing/</guid>
      <description>So far we built simple web applications that responded with the same message for each request. However, any real-world application is going to need a more complex way of handling requests, so in this article we will see how to create route handlers for specific routes and how to extract parameters from the request URI - we will explore the low-level Routing API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP .NET Core Startup</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-startup/</guid>
      <description>Any non-trivial application is going to need a mechanism to handle different types of requests and map them to specific services and middleware and configure services. This is accomplished through the &lt;code&gt;Startup&lt;/code&gt; class, which is also the entry point for any incoming HTTP request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP .NET Core Introduction</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>ASP.NET Core is a new open-source and cross-platform framework for building modern cloud based internet connected applications, such as web apps, IoT apps and mobile backends and a complete re-write of the 4.6 framework that came out last year and comes with a completely new architecture based on .NET Core. In this article we will see how to get started with ASP.NET Core.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
