<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>docker on radu&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://radu-matei.com/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in docker on radu&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/matei_radu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Radu M&lt;/a&gt; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://radu-matei.com/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Update Azure Container Instances with Docker Hub webhooks</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aci-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aci-update/</guid>
      <description>Back in July, Microsoft announced Azure Container Instances, a new Azure service delivering containers with great simplicity and speed and without any Virtual Machine infrastructure to manage. ACIs are the fastest and easiest way to run a container in the cloud. In this article we will see how to update Azure Container Instances based on webhooks from Docker Hub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins pipelines with Kubernetes </title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/kubernetes-jenkins-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/kubernetes-jenkins-azure/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this article is to show you how to deploy Jenkins to your Kuberentes cluster using Helm and write Jenkins pipelines that execute builds within pods in your cluster - all of this while replicating your Jenkins configuration and persisting everything with Kubernetes persistent storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hybrid Cluster: A CI/CD Story [Part 1] - Configuring a hybrid swarm mode cluster in Azure with acs-engine</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/hybrid-swarmmode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/hybrid-swarmmode/</guid>
      <description>We&#39;ll explore how to create a hybrid Docker Swarm Mode cluster with Linux and Windows agents, deploy it on Azure Container Service using ACS Engine, see how to connect to the cluster and manage it and finally how to deploy hybrid services with both Linux and Windows Server containers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dockerizing an ASP.NET Core application with GitHub, Docker Cloud and Azure</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-docker-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-docker-azure/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will take the simplest ASP.NET Core application, run it with Docker locally, then create Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment flows using a GitHub repository, Docker Cloud and an Azure virtual machine that will act as a node for Docker Cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>