<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Signalr on Radu Matei - Developer Evangelist</title>
    <link>https://radu-matei.com/categories/signalr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Signalr on Radu Matei - Developer Evangelist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://radu-matei.com/categories/signalr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with SignalR Alpha 2</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/signalr-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/signalr-core/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Introduction Chat, of course Adding a C# console client Handling connection and disconnection events Working with an MVC/WebApi application Streaming Sending binary data Redis scaleout Conclusion  Introduction  ASP.NET SignalR is a library for ASP.NET developers that simplifies the process of adding real-time web functionality to applications. Real-time web functionality is the ability to have server code push content to connected clients instantly as it becomes available, rather than having the server wait for a client to request new data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time ASP .NET Core</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/real-time-aspnet-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/real-time-aspnet-core/</guid>
      <description>What is this? This is an ASP .NET Core middleware for providing real-time functionality to your applications. To its core, this is a WebSockets middleware for ASP .NET Core applications with TypeScript / JavaScript and .NET clients.
 This is an open-source library available (for using and contributing) on GitHub.
 Why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t I use SignalR for real-time? Well, the reason is quite simple: SignalR for ASP .NET Core is still in its very incipient stages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a WebSockets middleware for ASP .NET Core</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-websockets-middleware/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-websockets-middleware/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE - February 2017 This article describes the latest development of websocket-manager and how to use it in your application.
While the general aspects provided in this article about creating a websockets middleware for Asp .Net Core are still valid, the specific information about the websocket-manager project have changed, since I updated a lot of parts.
The version of the project described in this article can still be found in the blog-article branch on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core MVC and SignalR Core</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-mvc-signalr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-mvc-signalr/</guid>
      <description>NOTICE This article is based on an old version of SignalR and is no longer functional / maintained - it is kept here only for historical purposes, you should visit this article that is current as of November / December 2017! All functionality of this article and much more can be found in the new article! 
Introduction In this article we will take a look at how to integrate ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>