<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>azure on radu&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://radu-matei.com/tags/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in azure on radu&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/matei_radu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Radu M&lt;/a&gt; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://radu-matei.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Update Azure Container Instances with Docker Hub webhooks</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aci-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aci-update/</guid>
      <description>Back in July, Microsoft announced Azure Container Instances, a new Azure service delivering containers with great simplicity and speed and without any Virtual Machine infrastructure to manage. ACIs are the fastest and easiest way to run a container in the cloud. In this article we will see how to update Azure Container Instances based on webhooks from Docker Hub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best of Both worlds: Azure App Service and Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/k8s-appsvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/k8s-appsvc/</guid>
      <description>In this article we will explore how to integrate Azure App Service and Kubernetes within the same Azure Virtual Network and consume Kubernetes services from an Azure App Service app without exposing them on the public Internet. There will be lots of situations when we want to use both the simplicity and features of a PaaS service (such as autoscaling, easy SSL, or any other cool feature) for a component and the flexibility of Kubernetes for others - in this article we will see how to achieve this without exposing services on the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started with Helm and Draft for Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/k8s-helm-draft-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/k8s-helm-draft-azure/</guid>
      <description>This post shows you how to automatize and simplify working with multiple Kubernetes clusters and multiple tools such as kubectl, helm or draft - creating a container image with your desired version of the tools and mounting the config files to the container</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes 1.8 on Azure</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/k8s18-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/k8s18-azure/</guid>
      <description>In this post you&amp;rsquo;ll see how to deploy Kubernetes 1.8 and later on Azure using ACS Engine, an open-source tool that creates the entire configuration for your orchestration cluster and deploys it on Azure Container Service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hybrid Cluster: A CI/CD Story [Part 1] - Configuring a hybrid swarm mode cluster in Azure with acs-engine</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/hybrid-swarmmode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/hybrid-swarmmode/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to create a hybrid Docker Swarm Mode cluster with Linux and Windows agents, deploy it on Azure Container Service using ACS Engine, see how to connect to the cluster and manage it and finally how to deploy hybrid services with both Linux and Windows Server containers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dockerizing an ASP.NET Core application with GitHub, Docker Cloud and Azure</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-docker-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-docker-azure/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will take the simplest ASP.NET Core application, run it with Docker locally, then create Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment flows using a GitHub repository, Docker Cloud and an Azure virtual machine that will act as a node for Docker Cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core MVC and SignalR Core</title>
      <link>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-mvc-signalr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radu-matei.com/blog/aspnet-core-mvc-signalr/</guid>
      <description>In this article we will explore how to get started with the Alpha 2 version of SignalR for ASP.NET Core 2.0 and understand streaming, sending binary data, using the Redis scaleout and, of course, chat!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>